Hey friends, we're glad you're still with us here at Microsoft Virtual Academy as we do our intro to ASP.NET Core.
大家好，很高兴你仍然关注我们微软虚拟学院，我们会继续介绍 ASP.NET Core
We're learning all about razor pages and our application.
我们将继续学习关于 razor 页面和应用程序的内容
-This module will be a little longer -Yes it will
-这模块将花比较长的时间去进行 -是的
And it will probably have us making some mistakes together,and that's okay.
它可能会误导我们犯一些错误,但这没关系
And we're gonna try not to hide anything from you.
我们要尽量不遗漏下任何东西
We are following the documentation as we hope that are, and maybe you can follow along.
我们会跟着文档去一步步操作,你也要这么做，并且可能会花更长时间
Pause, try stuff out, and maybe Google with Bing.
暂停一下,尝试去做,也许谷歌和必应一下是少不了的
Google with Bing.
Google 和 Bing~
If you have trouble and get stuck.
如果你有麻烦,卡住了
Yeah, and we will have links to the documentation right underneath this recording.
没关系,我们可以通过链接到文档对下的内容去了解详情（这个要去官网看呦~）
All right, so we're gonna try to make a CRUD page.
好吧,所以我们要试着做一个 CRUD 页面
What is CRUD?
什么是 CRUD?
Create,read, update, delete.
创建、读取、更新、删除
All right, so a CRUD application maps verbs from CRUD to verbs that we're used to using,like get is a get, so it would be like a read.
And if you're gonna create something, it would be a post.
如果你要创造一些数据,这就要用到 post 请求
So you'd fill out a form, you'd hit submit, and it would post the data, that's a create Then you can maybe read it back and look at in edit page or then maybe delete it.
当你在填写表格时,点击提交, post 请求将发送数据,经过一个创建过程后你可以在页面看到它,同样也可以编辑或删除
So if we succeed, we'll have the simple form,maybe create some customers, put them in a fake database And we'll be okay
如果顺利的话,我们会通过简单的形式创造一些虚拟信息,并把它们放在一个假的数据库,我们有信心~
Yeah, and I will be learning more about databases in the intermediate course as well
是的,我们以后将会学习更多关于数据库中间层的内容
Yes,well like a whole section on databases.
是的,他就像一个数据库整体的一部分
So for now, we're gonna be doing it in an in-memory database.
所以现在,我们会在内存中创建一个数据库
Okay, so let's do the best we can.
好吧,让我们尽我们所能来做吧
We're gonna use the same web application one that we created before.
我们将使用与之前创建的 web 应用相同的程序
We saw in the previous modules where we added MVC, but of course all of that stuff was added for us because we went File > New Project,and we picked Web Application, all right?
我们看下之前的模块,我们添加了 MVC ,当然我们之所以这么做是因为我们通过 文件>新项目 ,选择了 Web 应用程序,对吧?
So here in configure services, we've got AddMvc.
所以在配置服务,我们加上 AddMvc
But we're gonna make our little in-memory database here.
但我们需要有一个小的内存数据库
We're gonna say services.AddDbContext<>
我们在这里输入 services.AddDbContext<>
Yeah, and give it name
好的，给它一个名字
And we gonna create a thing called AppDbContext.
我们将创建一个名为 AppDbContext 的类
We can name it whatever we want to.
我们可以把他命名成喜欢的名字
We haven't written this yet, but we will.
我们还没有写这个,但我们以后会的
I'm gonna hit Ctrl+dot.
摁下 Ctrl + .
And it's saying, hey, do you need an AppDbContext?
它会提示,嘿,你需要一个AppDbContext吗?
Do you wanna go and generate one of those?
你要去生成一个吗?
I wanna go ahead and say yes.
我们选择,是的
So it's gone and done that, and we'll deal with that in a minute.
这样系统会去生成了,我们会在一分钟内处理掉它
And again, I will very likely make mistakes, so you'll bear with me I hope.
我很有可能再次犯错误,所以我希望你能原谅我
I opened up the parentheses there.
我在括号中添加内容
And I'm gonna pass in some options.
我将通过一些选项
-And the option I'm gonna pass in for my database context are options -UseInmemory.
-我要在 options 中进入数据库的上下文 -UseInmemory
-Use -In.
MemoryDatabase.
Yes, but the reason why that's not showing,that perfect.
是的,但这样写肯定是不完全的
-We need to add -why is that not showing up?
-我们需要添加 -为什么没有提示?
So we need to add the entity framework.
所以我们需要添加 entity framework
So we need to use
所以我们需要使用
And I probably should have added that first, and
可能应该说是补充,第一点
I would have gotten IntelliSense.
我们利用智能感知
-True -Let's try that.
-尝试 -让我们试一下
If we go back up to the top.
如果我们回去了
So we add the EntityFrameworkCore beforehand.
所以我们事先添加 Entity Framework Core
Look, you see that little arrow there that's pointing down?
看,你看到那个向下的小箭头?
That means that this method came in was included by the fact that we just did that UseIn.
这意味着,该方法包括了我们刚才添加进来的 UseIn
That's called an extension method,it's along for the ride.
这是一个扩展方法,它在其中
And you see it actually says extension,that wasn't there seconds ago
你看它实际就是一个拓展，那不是几秒钟之前的事
No, it wasn't.
不,它不是
Add InMemoryDatabase, some name All right,And then we look at the squiggle and we worry.
添加 InMemoryDatabase 的名字,下面有一个曲线，真叫人担心
Does the squiggle mean something?
下划线的意思是什么？
So, here it's saying AddDbContext.
所以,这里是说 AddDbContext
Well, we never really went and did anything with that AddDbContext.
好吧,我们从没有真正去引用 AddDbContext。
Let's go over there and fix that,I'm gonna right click and say go to definition.
我们去修复吧,点击右键去自定义
And let's work on our database context.
让我们搭建一个数据库环境
This is kind of standard stuff, so don't worry about it too much.
这是有标准对应的东西,所以不要担心太多
But basically this is representing the database.
但基本上这是代表数据库
I'm hitting Ctrl+dot there.
我现在摁下 Ctrl+.
And I'll say make it an AppDbContext,this is an constructor, all right?
我会让它成为 AppDbContext ,这是一个构造函数,对吧?
Okay, and we're gonna take in some options.
好的,我们会通过一些选项
-ContextOptions,Oops, optoons -Options?
-ContextOptions optoons -Options?
Options, pass up to the base class those options.
options ,通过 options 的基类
I'm gonna put that.
我要把它
What I'm trying to zoom and make it helpful for you, I end up making it worse for myself.
我想放的更大一点,让你能看清楚,但是那样我自己就很难受了
Well, at least you have other people in mind.
好吧,至少你有别人
-I do. And then -You have to set it of some sort.
-我这么做了 -你必须这么设置它
We have a set of, we're gonna say customers?
我们要设置，我们怎么命名？
So we have a set of customer.
我们命名为 Customer
Customer does not exist here.
Customer 并不存在
That's why it's squiggled out.
这就是为什么会出现下划线
And then we do a getter, setter, get ; set, okay?
然后我们做一个控制器和访问器,好吗?
Customer is squiggled out.
Customer 出现波浪线了
The type or namespace 'Customer' could not be found.
类型或命名空间 "Customer" 不存在
Well, that's true cuz we haven't made one yet.
真相是我们还没有去做呢！
We had not made it up.
我们没有做起来
l could type control dot, but l am gonna click show potential fixes.
我可以给它控制类型,但我点击显示潜在的修复
This is kind of interesting.
这是很有趣的
Here it's saying, well, I can go and make customer for you.
这里显示,我可以去为你去创建 customer
But look at this here.
但是看看这个
It's suggesting other packages that have the word customer and the name customer in it.
建议其他的存在这个词和名称的包
So these are other NuGet packages,packages up in the world.
在世界上有其他NuGet包
Yeah, ain't that cool?
是的,这不是很棒吗?
That's very cool.
这是非常酷的
-Package out there that has the word customer in it -Has the word customer in it
-包里面有 "customer" 这个词 -有 "customer"  这个词吗？
No, I don't want those.
不,我不想要这些
But if I was doing something with JSON or doing something with some technology that I knew I will need the NuGet packages, later it will go get it for me.
但如果我通过 json 或其他一些技术,我知道我需要 NuGet 包,之后它就会把它给我
So I'm gonna say generate in new file, that seems reasonable.
所以我要生成新的文件,似乎是合理的
-It does -All right, this generated that.
-是的 -那么来生成它吧
Now notice it just appeared.
现在注意到它就出现了
-There it is -And now I'm gonna right click and say go to definition
-这是 -现在点击右键要去定义
It is worth pointing out that I could also right click and say Peak Definition.
值得指出的是,我也可以右击然后选择 Peak Definition
-And could you write in there? -I could.
-你可以写在这里吗? -可以啊
I think that would be a little weird.
我觉得会有点奇怪
But then I can click on this little tab right here Promote to Document, and now I've jumped into that document.
但我可以点击这个小标签在这里拓展窗口,现在我已经跳转进来了
So I can peek and then if I type a little bit,I was like this is tiresome, then I could jump even higher.
我可以速览内容,如果我输入一点,我觉得这是烦人的,然后我可以跳得更高
-That's pretty smooth. -It is pretty smooth.
-操作起来很流畅 -确实很舒服
-All right, I'll show you another smooth tip. -I know it.
-好的,我将向你展示另一个提示方式 -我知道是什么
-Yeah? You wanna suggest? -The tab tab thing?
-是吗，你有建议吗? -使用 tab tab
-Yes, ready? -Prop Tab.
-是的,准备好了吗? -支持 tab
Tab, tab int Tab Id Enter Enter prop Tab Tab string Enter Tab Name.
Tab, tab int Tab Id 回车 回车 prop Tab Tab string 回车 Tab Name
-How cool is that? -It's cool, and I always forget to use it.
-这太酷了,不是吗? -是很酷,我总是忘记
-You gotta use it,There's so much good stuff in there -I always forget to use it and it's awesome.
-你必须使用它,在里边有这么好用的东西 -我总是忘记使用它,它太棒了
There's also propfull.
还有propfull
-What does that do? -That gives you a backing variable.
-这做什么呢? -给你一个支持变量
There's propa,which I don't know what it does but it's crazy.
还有 propa ,我不太知道,但它太疯狂了。
There's propg for a getter with a private setter.
这个控制器有一个 get 和一个私有的 set
Yeah, a bunch of stuff.
是的,很多东西
Have you done a blog post on all the properties
你做了博客的所有属性
There's a bunch of snippets,I could go all day.
有很多片段,我可以做一整天
But I'm just gonna use prop for now.
但是现在我要用道具
So this is customer, so customers have an ID,a unique ID.
这是客户,所以客户有一个ID、一个惟一的ID
And they have a name.
他们有一个名称
And they could probably have an email,they could have all these things.
他们可能有一个电子邮件,这些东西都有可能有
We'll start with name for now, but should name have some constraints?
我们从名字开始,但名字应该有限制吗?
It should,we have an idea of data annotation.
应该是有的,我们应该做一个数据的注释
There's annotation on that data, yes.
有注释的数据,是的
So one of the things is that you probably want someone to enter their name, right?
要做的事情中有一件事就是想让某人输入他们的名字,对吧?
-We wanna force them. -We wanna force them, so we want to make sure it some sort of required, right?
我们想强迫他们，我们想强迫他们,所以我们要确保某种需要,对吗?
So required, and I'm putting that as a notation here and I'm gonna hit Ctrl+dot, again.
所以需要我把这作为一个符号,点击 Ctrl+. 一下
When you learn that these things exist and you're thinking about them rather than typing in all this stuff for the using,you're just gonna type required.
当你学习这些东西的存在和你思考他们而不是输入使用所有这些东西,你就需要类型
Hit Ctrl+dot, and then hit Enter.
点击 Ctrl+. 然后回车
Line 1 just appeared there And then we'll force the length as well.
1号线就出现了,然后我们也会迫使长度
We'll be silly for a moment, we'll say a length of 10.
我想一会儿,设定长度为10吧
That's not a very good length.
这不是一个很好的长度
That is not a good length at all.
这不是一个合适的长度
But that might allow us to do some validation later.
我们先用它做一些验证
And then we'll change it to a longer length.
然后我们会改变它长的长度
All right, so let's back up for a second and see what we did here.
好吧,让我们回到了第二个,看看我们在这里做什么
So we have in our start up an InMemoryDatabase.
所以我们在启动一个 InMemoryDatabase
Not a SQLserver or a.
没有 SQL Server
Whatever just in memory database.
无论在内存数据库
We have a beginnings of a customer, unique ID and a name Some annotations on it, and then a little class here that's kind of empty.
我们有一个客户开始,惟一 ID 和名称一些注释,然后一个小类,是空的
That is our a list of customers and actually what's customer Singular here.
这是我们的 Customer 列表实际上这里的 Customer 有点奇怪
-Yeah. -That should be customers.
-是的. -应该是客户
-Okay, because, you have a set. -This is a set of customers.
-好吧,因为这必须要去设置 -这是客户的设置
So the one thing, how are we going to see this information?
还有一件事,我们怎么看到这个信息?
Well, we're going to need to probably put some in the database and then,once we have them in the database, list them out.
我们可能需要在数据库,然后放一些,一旦我们让他们在数据库列表中显示出来
Like how are we going to visually see it?
我们如何直观地看到?
Yeah, so there's a bit of a chicken and the egg problem there.
是的,像一个鸡和蛋的问题
Do we make the listing page first and list them out?
首先我们做清单页面列表出来吗?
But we really can't cuz we don't have any.
但我们不能，因为我们没有
-You don't anything, yeah. -Or we make a create page first.
-我们啥都没有呀 -或者我们先做一个页面出来
-So it's CRUD. -We'll do the C first, okay?
-这是 CRUD. -我们先把创建功能实现
-So over in -The pages folder.
-所以在 -页面文件夹
Pages, let's do create.
页面,我们来创建
Now, we're not going to say new file like we did before.
现在,我们不会说像我们之前做的新文件
No, you're going to create a new Razor Page or if you go to New File.
不,你要创建一个新的 Razor 页面或者如果你创建新文件
Let me do that again.
让我做一遍
Right click and I have two choices I have new.
右键点击和我有新有两个选择
-And then. -Page or I can say item.
-然后 -页面或者说项目
Yeah, New Item.
是的,新项目
And they should be the option to pick Razor Page.
他们应该选择 Razor 页面的选项
Right, so you got a couple different options here and this is all the different things that you could make.
对,所以你有几个不同的选项,这是你可以做的所有的事情
I'm gonna go and right click and say add Razor page, and I wanna point out that I'm not gonna do it for this because it will be a little bit cheating but after we're all done, first, we make you suffer.
我要和右单击,添加 Razor 页面,我想指出,我不会做这个,因为它将一点欺骗但我们都完成后,首先,我们让你受苦
And then we show you the easy way And then we show you the easy way
然后我们告诉你最简单的方法,然后我们告诉你最简单的方法
We could create that model and say Razor page is using entity framework CRUD, and then it will then scaffold or generate.
我们可以创建模型和 Razor 页面 CRUD是使用实体框架,然后将支架或生成
-Every single -All the hard parts that we're about to do.
-每一个 -所有困难的部分,我们要做的
But it's more fun to do, no no,it's more fun to do it ourselves, don't you think?
但它更有趣,不不,是更有趣的做自己,你不觉得吗?
-All right. -All right, lets do it ourselves.
-好吧 -好吧,让我们自己做吧
People can fast forward if they don't like it.
如果你们不喜欢，他们可以快进
The page name would be create.
页面名称将被创建
Uh-huh, and then we're gonna use a layout, we saw that.
我们会使用布局，我们看到
And then, here it says Generate PageModel,that's that code behind of that page model.
然后，在这里生成 PageModel ，那就是那个页面模型背后的代码。
We could say no and then do that in line, if we wanted to.
如果我们愿意，我们可以选择“不”，然后就这样做
All right. So let's see if that works.
好的。让我们看看这是否可行
Thinking, thinking, thinking.
思考思考
We're gonna watch in the right hand side here as create should appear.
我们将在右边观看，因为创造应该出现
And sticking well because it's doing quite a bit of scaffolding.
而且粘得很好，因为它做了很多脚手架
Well, it's scaffolding up some workforce but it's also gonna build the application to see if it still builds.
嗯，它正在架起一些员工的架子，但它也将构建应用程序来查看它是否仍在构建
And if it's running a scarf-folder.
如果它正在运行一个 scarf 文件夹
And scar folder is something that you can go on a nd read about and write your own if you feel like it.
SCAR文件夹是一种你可以去读和写你自己的东西，如果你喜欢它
So here we gotta create.
所以我们必须创造
-So let's see what we have in there -Let's see it gives us a page
-让我们看看里面有什么 -让我们看看它给了我们一个页面
It gave us a default model, a title, looks like a header, and then some validation scripts, and then presumably we can just start typing our pages or whatever.
它给了我们一个默认模型，一个标题，看起来像一个标题，然后是一些验证脚本，然后大概我们可以开始打字我们的页面或其他什么
Let's look at the backend,It made a create model that has a get.
让我们看看后端，它创建了一个具有 get 的创建模型
So this is the function that happens when we get stuff.
这就是我们得到东西时的作用
Okay.
好的
All right, so we're gonna need to make form code.
好的，所以我们需要制作表格代码
All right, so form that would have actually just one entry?
好吧，那么表格实际上只有一个条目？
Yeah, so we'll say enter your name, figure, all right.
是的，所以我们说输入你的名字，数字，好吧
And who knows if this will work, again, we're gonna learn.
谁知道这是否可行，我们将再次学习
Now, this is interesting, noticed that when I typed form Why is it in purple?
现在，这很有趣，注意到当我输入表格为什么它是紫色的？
Turns purple, so that is a tag helper, this is some related elements that are gonna be on the server for processing so the server knows about purple elements, and ill do some processing of them.
变成紫色，所以这是一个标签助手，这是一些相关的元素，将在服务器上进行处理，这样服务器就知道紫色元素，并且我会对它们进行一些处理
Typically when you're in HTML, you have like a P tag or an image tag or div, and that's just strings that get sent off to the client.
通常，当你在HTML中时，你有一个P标签或一个图像标签或div，而这只是被发送到客户端的字符串
But when we're generating this stuff on the server side,there might be an opportunity for ASP.NET Core to improve it,to change it, to add stuff.
但是当我们在服务器端生成这些东西时，ASP.NET核心可能会有机会改进它，改变它，添加一些东西
So it knows about form.
所以它知道形式
Form is a magic tag and we can go and type things like this,you see it says asp colon.
表格是一个魔术标签，我们可以去键入这样的东西，你看到它显示 ASP 冒号
Yeah, so is that indication that that is a tag helper or some sort of action?
是的，这是一个标记助手还是某种动作？
Right these things aren't html.
这些东西不是HTML
-No -Those are tag helpers
-并不是 -那些是标签助手
You'll never see asp hyphen something being sent all the way out to the browser.
你将永远不会看到 ASP 连字符被发送到浏览器
These are not HTML,They're hints to the server.
这些不是HTML，它们是服务器的提示
So if when we run this application, and we go into the F12 tools, we will not see- You shouldn't see those.
因此，如果我们运行这个应用程序，我们进入F12工具，我们将看不到-你不应该看到那些
-Okay -Exactly
-Okay -确切地
So we're gonna say form, this is gonna be basic method= a,yep see Get, post, put, delete
所以我们要说形式，这是基本方法= a ，看 GET,POST,PUT,delete
We'll say post So we're gonna go and post.
我们会用 post ，所以我们要使用 go 和 post
Here's the end of our form.
这是我们形式的结束
Say div, name, and then we'll need a text box.
div 名字，然后我们需要一个文本框
Yep so some sort of input tag.
是的，某种输入标签
Yep input,Now, this is interesting.
现在输入，这很有趣
We could do an input tag the way we usually do or we could say ASP.NET4.
我们可以按通常的方式做输入标记，也可以说是ASP.NET4
-Okay -And we're gonna say Customer.Name.
-Okay -我们要用 Customer.Name
-Okay -See how it's all purple?
-Okay -看它怎么都是紫色的？
That ASP 4 is gonna look at that model, okay?
ASP 4会使用那个模型，好吗？
Now, it's saying here, I don't know what a Customer is.
现在，这里说的是，我不知道 Customer 是什么
What's going on with that?
这是怎么回事？
It's never heard of Customer before.
以前从来没有听说过 Customer
We'll come back and fix that in a second.
我们一会儿再来解决
Then we'll have an input for submitting that form, okay?
然后我们输入一张表格，好吗？
But we have a problem here,where it doesn't know what Customer is.
但我们在这里遇到了一个问题，就是不知道 Customer 是什么
What is the model for this page?
这个页面的模型是什么？
-Right, it's the -The Create
-好的，这是 -是创建
CreateModel, so let's go look at that.
CreateModel, 让我们来看一看
Peek into Definition, okay.
查看一下定义，好的
I wanna point out how I'm moving around.
我想指出我是怎么四处走动的
I'm right clicking and saying Go To Definition is also a hotkey for that.
我右击，对此定义一个热键
So this is an important reminder, just as a programmer,you don't wanna necessarily find yourself going over and looking around all the files all the time.
这是一个重要的提醒，就像一个程序员一样，你不需要发现自己到处都在浏览所有的文件
-You can navigate -To it, right?
-你可以导航 -对吧？
To it directly, you can navigate logically, as they say.
直接说，你可以像他们所说的那样在逻辑上进行导航
-Okay, all right. -Did you?
-Okay, 好吧. -你呢？
-Cut something out from -Yeah
-从这里剪掉 -好的
-Okay -Great.
-好的 -不错.
-There we go -I cut out CreateModel, thank you.
-我们继续 -我剪下了 CreateModel ，谢谢你
Right so, our create model is gonna need to know about customers, because that's gonna show up on the page.
好的那么，我们的创建模型需要了解客户，因为这会出现在页面上
So public Customer, that's a type.
所以公众客户，这是一种类型
-That's a name -You can tell by the color.
-这是名字 -你可以根据颜色辨别
It's a little confusing.
这有点混乱
But, the property is called Customer, and the type is called Customer.
但是，该属性称为 Customer ，类型称为 Customer
And, this is going to need that database context,so we are going to make a little Database here.
而且，这将需要数据库上下文，所以我们将在这里制作一个小数据库
And this is just being the voice of the person doing this at home.
而这正是在家里做这件事的人的声音
Why have you made it private read only?
为什么你只让它成为私人阅读？
So that's a great point.
这是一个很好的观点
I don't want people who get a hold of create model to be poking around and talking directly to the database.
我不想让那些持有创建模型的人四处乱转，直接与数据库对话
So, it's gonna be private, just for me where me is CreateModel.
所以，它将是私人的，就我而言，我就是CreateModel
And it's read only which means I'm gonna assign it once, and I don't want anyone to touch it after that.
它是只读的，这意味着我要把它分配一次，我不想让任何人在那之后接触它
-Yeah. Okay -So I'm making it just for me and making sure I can't mess with it afterwards.
-Yeah. Okay -所以我只是为我做，确保我以后不会弄乱它
Excellent, excellent question.
确实是个好问题
-So then, we'll make our -CreateModel Our constructor.
-那么，我们将制造 -CreateModel 我们的构造器
And remember how dependency injection works.
还记住依赖注入是如何工作的
We don't make an AppDbContext we ask for one.
我们不要求一个 AppDB 上下文
We ask for it by putting it in our constructor.
我们把它放在我们的构造函数中
We can have as many of these as we want,We can have food and bar, etc, etc, etc.
我们可以有很多我们想要的，我们可以有食物和酒吧等等
This is the one we want for now.
这就是我们现在想要的
And then I'm just going to say hey, this one equals this one.
然后我要说，嘿，这个等于这个
I'm going to squirrel it away and hang onto it, so now I've got one.
我要松开它然后挂上它，所以现在我有一个
So that says there's this database, and I want to know about it.
所以说有这个数据库，我想知道
This says there's a customer.
这说明有一个 customer
If I go back over to create, I can hover over that and see it's getting me probably IntelliSense too.
如果我回去创造，我可以在上面徘徊，看到它也让我很有智慧
Yep, see. Now, it is.
是的，明白了。现在，它是的
So, it knows about customer because it's hanging off of the model.
所以，它知道客户是因为它脱离了模型
So as we're running the application.
所以我们正在运行应用程序
Technically, I should be able to go to this page,hover over customer name and see what names we've put in there?
从技术上讲，我应该能够到这个页面，悬停在客户的名字上，看看我们放在那里的名字？
You should be able to click on that,you should be able to have IntelliSense.
你应该能够点击它，你应该能够拥有智能感知
If you did a break point,you should be able to stop in here at some point and look at that, and we'll do that in a little bit.
如果你做了一个突破点，你应该能够在这里停留在某个点，看看，我们会做一点点
What we need, though, is we need to bind this form.
我们需要的是，我们需要约束这种形式
We're saying this input for customer name.
我们说的是客户姓名的输入
When I hit submit, we need to catch it on the server side.
当我点击提交时，我们需要在服务器端捕获它
I call it surviving the journey.
我称之为旅途中的幸存
Okay. Yeah, it's a good point.
可以。是的，这是一个很好的观点
It does need to survive the journey.
它确实需要在旅途中幸存下来
So I'm gonna get rid of this OnGet here.
所以我要把这件东西扔掉
So we're gonna do a post.
所以我们要做一个帖子
You can say OnPost.
你可以在 OnPost
You could do it like this but the right way to do it is like this.
你可以这样做，但是正确的方法就是这样
-Async? -Async, which means don't block, and we're gonna have a task that returns some action.
-异步？ -异步，这意味着不阻塞，我们将有一个任务返回一些动作
We might be doing something after this and I'm gonna say on OnPostAsync.
我们可能在这之后做点什么，我会在事后说
And it's giving me a little complaint here saying!
它给我一个小小的抱怨！
You didn't do a wait and you haven't returned a value.
你没有等待，你还没有返回数值
Code paths, not all code paths return a value.
代码路径，并非所有代码路径返回值
That's cuz we haven't done anything yet.
这是因为我们还没有做任何事情
So, when someone posts back, they hit submit,and it posts back to here.
所以，当有人发布帖子时，他们会点击提交，然后返回到这里
We would really like customer to have stuff in it.
我们真的希望客户有东西在里面
-Yes -And so there's a couple things here.
-是的 -所以这里有两件事
And then we need to make sure that the state of that model is valid, that someone hasn't messed with it.
然后我们需要确保那个模型的状态是有效的，有人没有弄错它
So I'm gonna say if ModelState.IsValid,or if it's not, pardon me- I was about to say something.
所以我要说，如果MealStal.是有效的，或者如果不是，请原谅我——我要说点什么
No I appreciate that,Then return the page back to itself to say now I'm done.
不，我很感激，然后把页面还给自己，说现在我完了
If I hover over page you can see it returns a page result,which is a kind of action.
如果我在页面上徘徊，你会看到它返回一个页面结果，这是一种行为
Returning a page is an action.
返回页面是一个动作
If we get this far, now I'm gonna say db,remember when I say db?
如果我们走这么远，现在我要说 DB ，记得我说 DB 吗
-Yes -What is db?
-是的 -什么是DB？
It is a applicationDB context.
它是 AppultDB 上下文
In there is customers, plural.
里面有 customers ，复数
-And we want to add one. -.Add()
-我们想增加一个 -.Add()
We'll pass in the customer that we just got handed.
我们会把刚才交给的顾客交给我们
And then we'll say, hang out for a minute, await.
然后我们说，等一会儿，等等
And we'll say, db.SaveChanges,And async means don't wait
我们会说, db.SaveChanges,async 意味着不需要等待
Then we will go and return,not a page, because we're on the create page.
然后我们会返回，而不是一页，因为我们在创建页面
We really wanna return to the list.
我们真的想回到名单上
Yeah, so you're doing a redirect?
是的，所以你在重定向？
We're gonna do a redirect, exactly.
我们要做一个重定向
And we haven't got a place to go yet,But we'll say redirect to page
我们还没有地方可去，但是我们会说重定向到页面
Okay. And you can see that there's options like redirect to page permanent, which would be a 301.
可以。你可以看到有重定向到页面永久性的选项，这将是301
-Okay -Http 301
-Okay -HTTP 301
We're gonna do a 302 because this is just a standard kind of redirect,Let's just say /Index
我们要做一个302，因为这只是一种标准的重定向
And I think we should probably just say /,but we'll see what happens.
我想我们应该说/，我想我们应该说一下，但是我们看看会发生什么
If people wanted to learn more about 301s,302s, do you have any recommendations?
如果人们想了解更多关于301S、302S的信息，你有什么建议吗？
-The Internet. -Correct
-互联网 -正确
I would search around for that kind of stuff.
我会到处寻找这种东西
Ultimately look at the docs.
最后看看文档
-Yeah -But redirect to page is a standard thing and again if you hover over it, it says right there Status302Found.
-是的 -但是重定向到PAGE是一个标准的事情，如果你在它上面徘徊，它会在那里找到STATES302
But if I said RedirectToPagePermanent.
但是如果我说 RedirectToPagePermanent
We would change it?
我们会改变它吗?
Change it to a 301, which would tell the search engine,don't ever come back here and ask me about this again.
将它改为301，这将告诉搜索引擎，不要再回来这里问我这个问题了
Don't ever talk to me again go here.
不说了，继续吧
-All right -That's what that means
-好的 -就是那个意思
I'm paranoid so anyway,you never wanna do that when you're doing database work.
我是偏执狂，无论如何，当你做数据库工作的时候，你从来都不想这么做
You always wanna be temporary, okay?
你总是想要临时的，好吗？
Okay. All right, and if you really,really, really wanna upset your coworkers.
好吧，如果你真的真的真的想打扰你的同事
You could move your curly braces.
你可以移动你的大括号
Yeah.
And do stuff like this.
然后做这样的事情
And if you really wanna be possibly buggy,you could even do stuff like this.
如果你真的想做一辆车，你甚至可以做这样的事情
-Where that's all one line -Yeah?
-这就是一条线 -是吗?
But you might have other stuff that you wanna do.
但你可能还有其他的事情要做
Okay. Some people that really bothers them, some people it doesn't.
可以。有些人真的很烦他们，有些人不喜欢
-For me- Does it bother you?
-对我来说 -打扰你了吗？
I kinda like it on one line if it's not that big of a deal.
我喜欢它在一行如果它不是那么大的交易
You know what I mean,but as soon as you have an extra line then you're gonna go and undo it and take it apart.
你知道我的意思,但是一旦你有一个额外的线，那么你会去解开它，并把它拆开
It's stylistic,so it's not really a best practice for someone to know of right now.
它是风格化的，所以对于现在知道的人来说这不是最好的练习
No, for right now, I just think it's nice to have everything fit on one line like that.
不，现在，我认为把每件事情都放在这样一条线上是很好的
But using the curly mustaches.
但要用卷曲的胡子
Is curly braces,they look like a mustache if you turn your head.
是卷发，如果你转个头，他们看起来像胡子
That's a best practice.
这是最好的做法
It still gets us, that when people say curly braces, and I don't know what they're talking about
当人们说花括号，我不知道他们在说什么的时候，我们还是用括号
-What do you call them? -cuz I use brackets
-你怎么称呼他们？ -因为我使用括号
You call them brackets?
你称它们为括号？
So you have brackets, curly brackets, square brackets, so.
所以你有括号，卷筒，方括号
-Scandalous -Okay
-不好听 -好吧
-You're fancy -That is pretty intense.
-你很喜欢 -这是相当刺激的
-Yeah -Okay, now I'm going to put a break point here.
-Yeah -Okay, 现在我要在这里放一个断点
-Okay. And we'll see if this works -All right.
-Okay ，我们看看这是否行得通
It might very well not work.
这很可能不起作用
-Fingers crossed and toes -No, it's probably not gonna work
-双手合十祈祷 -不, 它可能不会工作
Lower your expectations now.
降低你的期望
This is in create, right?
这是创建，对吧？
-So I have to hit /create -Yep
-所以我必须点击/创建 -是的
Okay
Did we bind it?
我们绑定好了吗？
-Yeah see what's happening? -Nothing.
-是的，看到发生什么事了吗？ -没有
-No -And if we go and do a view source.
-啥都没有 -如果我们去做一个视图源
-And you go to? -Okay.
-你要再怎么做? -Okay
I just want to show the people the form first.
我只是想先给大家看一下表格
Some things showed up on the input that's kinda cool.
一些东西出现在输入上，这有点酷
-That's kinda nice -That is
-那很不错 -就是啊
We didn't type that, right, remember?
我们没有打字，对吗？记得吗？
So we're getting stuff on the input that we did not expect,which is cool.
所以我们在输入中得到了我们没有预料到的东西，这很酷
I bet there's some request verification.
我打赌有一些请求验证
Yeah, they put a request verification token to keep people from tampering with our stuff.
是的，他们提出了一个请求验证令牌来防止人们篡改我们的东西
There is your name=Customer.Name.
这里是你的 name=Customer.Name.
And it generated an id for us as well.
它也产生了我们的身份证
But you can see that nothing's happening.
但你可以看到什么都没有发生
On Customer, actually I wanna put a break point a little higher up, and then I'll explain to you what's going on.
对客户来说，实际上我想把一个突破点提高一点，然后我会向你解释发生了什么
Let's see if we can even get to the post.
让我们看看我们能不能通过 post
Okay, do a debug session again /create.
好，再试一次调试/创建
So I would've expected.
所以我早就料到了
-To hit that break point -To hit that break point, so that's concerning.
-击中那个断点 -击中那个断点，这就是问题所在
But I know that I need to say BindProperty on the customer which is to tell it I want this customer object filled out with the form information, right?
但我知道我需要对客户说BDIN属性，告诉客户我希望这个客户对象填写表单信息，对吧？
-Yeah. -And right now I don't have that.
-Yeah. -现在我没有
So let's take a look, and try this again.
让我们来看一看，然后再试一次
The customer is gonna get created and filled up with information bound to those form fields.
客户将被创建并填写与这些字段绑定的信息
If that doesn't work then I've forgotten something and we will go and have a little debugging which will be fun as well.
如果这不起作用，那么我就忘记了什么，我们会去做一个小调试，这将是有趣的
They say the definition of insanity is doing the same thing over and over and expecting a different result.
他们说精神错乱的定义是一遍又一遍地做同样的事情，期望得到不同的结果
So let's take a look.
让我们来看一看
It's probably something obvious.
这可能是显而易见的事情
So we've got a form, we've got our input, we've got our method.
所以我们有一张表格，我们有我们的输入，我们有我们的方法
I said post, does it matter if it's all caps?
我说，如果所有的帽子都有关系吗？
That would be odd if it did.
如果真是这样，那就太奇怪了
So it doesn't matter.
所以没关系
The tag helper exists already in view imports,the form is there.
标签助手已经存在于视图导入中，表单就在那里
The only thing l didn't add is the validation summary, okay?
我唯一没有添加的是验证摘要，好吗？
-Okay -All right, so l am putting in a long name, Fancy Pants, and nothing's happening.
-Okay -好吧，所以我要穿一个长长的名字，华丽的裤子，什么也没发生
-No -No, and am realizing that I've got my form with my input for customer name,but I put my validation summary outside the form.
-不 -不，我意识到我已经有了我的客户姓名输入表格，但是我把我的验证总结放在表格之外
-Okay -So I am gonna put it inside the form,cuz it's validating the form.
-好的 -所以我会把它放在表单里面，因为它正在验证表单
And then I'm gonna hit Refresh, Fancy Pants, see and it says the Field Name, must be a string with maximum length of 10.
然后我要刷新，华丽的裤子，看到它说的是字段名称，必须是一个最大长度为10的字符串
I'm getting that validation for free, right?
我免费得到验证，对吧？
And where did that 10 come from?
那10人来自哪里？
We set it in, yep, right there.
我们把它放进去了，没错，就在那里
We set it right there.
我们把它放在那里
So maybe we'll change that to like 25, or something like that.
也许我们会把它变成25，或者类似的东西
Some people have really long names like in my country who have names which are 50, so maybe 100?
有些人在我的国家有很长的名字，名字有50个，也许是100个？
I'll make 49 and then that one 50 person,they're gonna suffer.
我要49，然后50个人，他们会受罪
-Man -inclusion. But the point is it's driven by
-人 -包括。但关键是它是由它们驱动的
-By them -By them, okay?
-通过他们 -通过他们, 好吗?
And then one other thing- So it'd be the same if someone did entered something that wasn't an email, right?
-还有一件事 -如果有人输入了不是电子邮件的东西，情况也会一样，对吧？
Yeah, it could be an email, it could be,you can put in validation information however you want,and you could even put in custom, regular expressions, or even write your own custom validators.
是的，它可以是电子邮件，它可以是，你可以放入验证信息，不管你想要什么，你甚至可以放入自定义，正则表达式，甚至写自己的自定义验证器
So they could be as sophisticated as you want.
所以他们可以像你想要的那样复杂
-Okay -You could also, I believe, say, I want a span.
-好吧 -你也可以说，我想要一个跨距
And say asp-validation-for, and you could go and do a field by field validation, okay.
并用ASP验证，你可以去做一个实地验证，好吧
So here I'm saying this is my summary of all the different things, this is a specific validation for Customer Name.
所以我说这是我对所有不同事物的总结，这是对客户名称的具体验证
Okay, let's see what that looks like And that might look a little different so if I come over here, come back over here and hit Refresh,oops I actually don't hit Refresh.
好吧，让我们看看这是什么样子，这可能看起来有点不同，所以如果我来到这里，回到这里，点击刷新，OOP，我实际上不刷新
I need to run my app again cuz I stopped it.
我需要再次运行我的应用程序，因为我停止了它
Okay.
Okay
Run that again.
再跑一遍
Go to Create.
去创建
I think we made it really long this time, right?
我想这次视频我们做的真的很长，对吧？（您二位还知道呀，累死我啦~）
And I tab away and it says it must be a string with a maximum length of 49.
我把它拿走，它说它必须是一个最大长度为49的绳子
Okay.
Okay
But I like the main validation stuff so we'll leave that like that, okay?
但是我喜欢主要的验证，所以我们就这样离开，好吗？
Now, let's go back to our break points and run our debugger this time, and see if we can see the customer get found.
现在，让我们回到我们的断点，并运行我们的调试器这次，看看我们是否可以看到客户找到
Okay.
Okay
We had looked in the F12 developer tools before,we could see what's happening on the wire.
我们以前看过F12开发工具，我们可以看到电线上发生了什么
This is a good way to kinda just see what's happening as you do your posts.
这是一个很好的方式，看看你做什么，当你做你的帖子
-So when you're looking, so you went to Developer Tools -Yeah. And the network?
-所以当你在看的时候，你就去开发工具了 -是啊。网络呢？
I went to dot dot dot Developer Tools and we're under Network.
我想用 dot 开发工具，在网络下
Okay. I will go and probably and clear it out, and then we'll put in Maria, okay.
可以。我会去把它弄清楚，然后我们就去Maria，好吗？
Yep, there we go, so if you hover over that.
是的，我们走了，所以如果你悬停在上面
If we hover over Customer, see,because customer has a name.
如果我们悬停在客户身上，请看，因为客户有名字
Yeah. Customer.name, and we name the field Customer.name, and we told it, hey,bind, we want you to participate.
是啊。客户。名称，我们命名字段客户。名称，我们告诉它，嘿，BIN，我们希望你参与
You automatically showed up in there.
你会自动出现在那里
-Okay -And I can put a little pin there as well
-Okay -我也可以放一个小别针
If I was gonna do lots of debugging sessions,then I can keep you there as a post to note and watch customer name change over time.
如果我要做很多调试会话，那么我可以把你放在那里作为一个帖子来记录和观察客户名称的变化
-That's a good one -We can go and see if the model state is valid, it is.
-那是一个不错的选择 -我们可以去看看模型状态是否有效
-What is the green button, that's a play like -Yeah, go to that point.
-什么是绿色按钮，这是一个游戏 -是的，到那一点
Play up to that point, and then stop.
玩到那一点，然后停下来
So here, I'm gonna go and Add that customer to the database.
所以，我要把这个客户添加到数据库中
Save it to the database,which of course is an in-memory database.
将其保存到数据库中，这当然是内存数据库
And then we'll redirect Now we had put in slash, but I'm not sure that's gonna work.
嗯，然后我们重定向，现在我们已经投入了斜杠，但我不确定这会起作用
Should we should we see about their pages, just in case?
我们应该看看他们的网页，以防万一吗？
-Yeah, see? -Okay.
-是的，看到了吗？ -Okay
It's says no page / matches this value.
它没有页面/匹配这个值
So you have to give the specific name
所以你必须给出具体的名字
I need to say index, which was what our main page is here
我需要 index ，在这里这是我们的主页
So index, okay?
Now we'll confirm if that that works.
现在我们确认这是否可行
I can hit F5 to go and debug, or I can hit Ctrl+F5,which I like to do, cuz it starts up a little faster,if I know that I'm not gonna do a debugging session.
我可以命中F5去调试，或者我可以点击CTRL+F5，我喜欢这样做，因为它启动得快一点，如果我知道我不会做调试会话
But this time you hit F5?
但这次你击中了F5？
I hit Ctrl+F5 to go faster.
我点击Ctrl +F5以加快速度
Okay, so it redirected me to index but of course I haven't done anything on index that's interesting yet.
好的，它让我重定向到索引，当然我还没有做任何有意思的索引
That will be the next part, right.
这将是下一个部分，对
So you could also probably send a message saying
所以你也可以发送一个信息说
I can say customer updated,or whatever.
我可以说客户更新，或者什么
But let's rip out this whole section here.
但是让我们把整个部分撕掉
-Okay, very nice -And put a list of contents.
-Okay ，非常好 -并列一个目录
-Okay -Is that cool?
-Okay -酷吗？
So where's our index?
那么我们的索引在哪里呢？
So this is all this carousel and all this stuff.
这就是所有的旋转木马和所有这些东西
All the fancy bootstrap.
所有的花样引导
I'm gonna actually collect this.
我要收集这个
And then you comment it out?
然后你评论一下？
Actually, no, I'm just gonna be awesome and just like toss it.
事实上，不会的，我会就像扔硬币一样棒棒
Wow. Yeah, but this is a way,if you wanna go hunting for the other side of the div,you can just fold these up, see that this matches this.
真的。是的，但是这是一种方式，如果你想去寻找另一个DIV，你可以把它们折叠起来，看看这与这个匹配
Fold it up, select over it and toss it.
把它折叠起来，选择它并扔它
Cool, all right.
酷，好吧
So let's make our form.
所以，让我们形成自己的形式
And this will be on the index page, right?
这将在索引页上，对吗？
We'll have method="post", and this will be a table.
是的。我们将有方法=“POST”，这将是一个表
All right.
好的
It's okay to use tables, if it is a table of data.
如果表是数据表，可以使用表
So many people complain about tables being a bad idea.
很多人抱怨表是个坏主意
I think that's kind of funny,It's a table,It's okay to have a table.
我觉得这很有趣，这是一张表，有一张表是可以的
So we'll have a head for our table, and we'll have our ID row.
所以我们有一张表，我们会有 ID 行
-Yep -Oops, and we'll have ID.
-Yep -哎呀，我们会有 ID 的
Then we'll have Name, we don't really need to show the database ID but for now let's show it.
然后我们将有名字，我们不需要显示数据库ID，但是现在让我们来展示它
All right,So do you have to create a tbody, okay yeah,you're way ahead of me.
所以你必须创建一个 tbody ，好吧，是的，你在我前面
No, it's okay. Table body
不，没关系 Table body
But now I need a row for each.
但现在我需要每一行
So would you put it in the row, or would you,so I am presumed that you need to go for every contact within.
所以你会把它放在队列中，还是你，所以我推测你需要去寻找里面的每一个联系人
Exactly.
确切地
So I'm gonna have like a FOR SOMETHING HERE.
所以我会有类似于 FOR SOMETHING HERE 的东西
Then a couple of cells, table cells, and then maybe a, I don't know,like a link to edit and a delete button.
然后是两个单元格，表格单元格，也许是A，我不知道，像一个编辑和删除按钮的链接
Yeah.
-Okay, you see how I'm kind of sketching it out -You're sketching it out
-好吧，你看我是怎么画出来的 -你正在描绘它
-Okay. Wild -what's it called?
-Okay. 野生 -它叫什么？
-Pseudocode or something? -Pseudocode,It's a little pseudocode here
-Pseudocode 或者 something? -Pseudocode ,这里有点伪代码
So now I wanna say at.
所以现在我想说
For each yeah. And this is a snippet-
对每个人来说是的。这是一个片段
-Yeah -Tab, Tab, and then I'm gonna say for each,contact, oops, contact in, in what?
-Yeah -Tab, Tab, 然后我会说，每个人，联系，OOP，联系进来，在什么？
In Model.
在模型中
Now where is our customers?
现在我们的客户在哪里？
Okay, so remember before when we were doing our create model?
好的，所以记得在我们做我们的创建模型之前吗？
We needed to have the customers come from somewhere.
我们需要让顾客从某个地方来
Yeah. Now we're in a totally different page.
是啊。现在我们完全不一样了
Yeah, so we have to have the customers.
是的，所以我们必须有顾客
We have to have the customers, right?
我们必须有客户，对吧？
Yeah. So I'm gonna just take a break here.
是啊。所以我要在这里休息一下
And I'm gonna jump over to the index model cuz we can't really make our table till we have a little bit more, okay?
我要跳到 index 模型，因为我们不能真的做我们的表，直到我们有多一点，好吗？
And I'm gonna break a couple of cardinal rules that I'm gonna copy paste a little code,because I'm gonna need this similar app database.
我要打破一些基本规则，我要复制粘贴一个小代码，因为我需要这个类似的应用程序数据库
This app db context which is gonna save myself a moment of time here.
这个App DB上下文将在这里节省我自己的时间
So we've got our app context, right?
所以我们有了应用程序上下文，对吧？
We're gonna have our index page model.
我们将有索引页模型
Now before, when we create a customer,we create one customer.
现在，当我们创建一个客户时，我们创建了一个客户
But here our model is different cuz we're gonna have a list of customers on this page, right?
但在这里我们的模型不同，因为我们会在这一页上有一个客户列表，对吧？
So our model is different.
所以我们的模型是不同的
And we'll do a get and then a private set so that only we can set it.
我们会做一个GET，然后是一个私有集合，这样我们才可以设置它
-All right, and then, in the OnGet, We'll say OnGet -One line below, OnGetAsync, okay
-好的,然后在 OnGet 我们会在 OnGet -One 下面一行, OnGetAsync, okay
-OnGetAsync, right? -We're gonna load up customers.
-OnGetAsync, 是吗? -我们要去接客户
Where do we get them from?
我们从哪里得到它们？
The database and this is right there.
数据库就在这里
We're getting them out of customers.
我们把他们从客户那里弄出来
And then there's this other little bit of thing that you can add on to make things a little bit faster.
还有另外一点你可以补充的东西让事情稍微快一点
You can say AsNoTracking.
你可以 AsNoTracking.
And I'll show you what that means in a second.
我会告诉你这意味着什么
And we're gonna turn these customers into a list of customers.
我们会把这些客户变成客户名单
So we're chaining things together,we're saying give me these customers.
所以我们把事情联系在一起，我们是说给我这些客户
And we're not gonna keep track of them changing.
我们不会跟踪他们的变化
You see it says disabling change tracking is useful for read-only scenarios.
您可以看到禁用更改跟踪对于只读场景是有用的
Change tracking is watching like keeping a track of all the different things you could change so that you know how to make a database update.
就像跟踪所有你可以改变的事物的轨迹，这样你就知道如何进行数据库更新
So if I had a list of customers, and I wanted to watch all of them and change their names, that would give the database system entity framework that we're gonna learn about later all the information it needs about how to only change the bits that change, how to only change the database.
所以，如果我有一个客户列表，我想看所有的人，并改变他们的名字，这将给出数据库系统实体框架，我们稍后将了解所有关于如何只更改这些位的信息，如何只更改数据库
But we're just getting a list, so we're gonna say, don't track these, just give me a list.
但我们只是得到一个列表，所以我们要说，不要跟踪这些，只要给我一个清单
So customers, no tracking, give me a list, so that's cool.
所以客户，没有跟踪，给我一个清单，所以很酷
And I think we'll leave that like that for now.
我想我们现在就这样离开
We'll go back over to index.
我们将回到 index
And now that model, the page behind us has customers.
现在这个模型，我们后面的页面有客户
Look, customers shows up, see, which is nice.
看，顾客出现了，看，哪一个很好
So then I think I can put my tr in here.
所以我想我可以把我的 tr 放在这里
And I'm hoping, remember, I said contact, I should say customer.
我希望，记住，我说联系，我应该说客户
Customer singular, foreach customer,that means that the customer variable is now available to me customer.Id.
客户单数，前额客户，这意味着客户变量现在可以给我客户
-Everything's connected -Yep, cool, let's try that.
-一切都是相连的 -酷，让我们试试看.
Okay. And then we'll do the rest,cuz I don't know if this is gonna work yet.
然后我们做剩下的事情，因为我不知道这是否可行
Now I'm using an in-memory database, so every time I run this, it's gonna go away.
现在我使用的是内存数据库，所以每次运行这个数据库，它都会消失
So it's just a throw away database.
所以这是一个一次性数据库
-I need to do better -I need to maybe make tests later, and I survived the journey.
-我需要做得更好 -我需要以后再做测试，我在旅途中幸存下来
-You did -Let's see, but as soon as I shut you down, it's gonna be gone.
-你需要这么做 -让我看看，但是一旦我把你关了，它就不见了
-So if you refresh the page -You're here,you're still there, right?
-如果你刷新页面 -你在这里，你还在那里，对吧？
You're there until I close it, until I close this browser.
你在那里直到我关闭它，直到我关闭这个浏览器
Or not if I close the browser, pardon me,until I stop the web server.
或者，如果我关闭浏览器，请原谅我，直到我停止Web服务器
-So, okay -Yeah, thanks, cool, so now we've got create.
-好了 -谢谢，很酷，所以现在我们有了创建功能
We should probably put a button down there at the bottom somewhere.
我们应该把按钮放在下面的某个地方
We've got some validation, we've got our database,looking at our friends And this is doing a thing called Post Redirect Get.
我们有一些验证，我们有我们的数据库，看我们的朋友，这是做一个叫做邮政重定向的东西
So I'm here, I hit a post, we do a redirect, and then we do a get, and then we would get this stuff here.
所以我在这里，我打了一个帖子，我们做了一个重定向，然后我们做了一个get，然后我们得到了这个东西
So this is a PRG, Post Redirect Get.
所以这是一个PRG，邮政重定向获得
There's lots of articles on the Internet about that.
网上有很多关于这方面的文章
Now let's make a link to theoretically go and edit these things.
现在让我们从理论上链接并编辑这些东西
-Okay -And then we'll have a button for Delete.
-Okay -然后我们有一个删除按钮
These things don't exist on the backend yet,but we can- So yeah,so we don't have an edit page yet.
这些东西在后端还不存在，但是我们可以——所以是的，所以我们还没有编辑页面
-We don't -Okay. We can make a link
-我们没有 -可以。我们可以建立联系
Now I could go and put in a link, href.
现在我可以走了，把一个链接，HREF
You've done this before a million times.
你已经做过一百万次了
And say /edit and then put in strings and stuff.
然后说/编辑，然后把字符串和东西
But remember we talked about how great tag helpers are.
但是记住，我们谈到了标签助手的伟大之处
-Yeah -What if we went and said asp-page and then we could go and say there's an edit page and then it would figure out what the URL would look like.
-Yeah -如果我们去说ASP页面，然后我们可以说有一个编辑页面，然后它就会知道URL会是什么样子
-Okay -All right, and then it could even express the route a certain way.
-Okay -然后它甚至可以以某种方式表达路线
And we'll talk about routes in a minute.
我们将在一分钟内谈论路线
I think it's route-id.
我认为这是路由器ID
And I think we called it customer.Id.
我想我们命名为 customer.Id
So it's gonna take that customer's id so we want to basically make a page that looks like /edit/2, /edit/3, right?
所以它将采取客户的ID，所以我们想基本上制作一个页面，看起来像/编辑/ 2，/编辑/ 3，对吗？
And that's the route id that's gonna get added onto that.
这就是将要添加到那个的路径ID
Okay, so the next thing you have is a button?
好吧，那么接下来你有一个按钮？
Yeah, we'll do a button type="submit" and this is going to be handled by the page.
是的，我们会做一个按钮类型=“提交”，这将由页面来处理
-Okay -Button's gonna be a little different.
-Okay -按钮会有点不同
The reason that we're doing a button in an href is so you can see the difference between a link,and how links behave, and buttons.
我们在HREF中做一个按钮的原因是，你可以看到一个链接和链接的行为和按钮之间的区别
A link is gonna navigate somewhere.
一个链接将导航到某处
-Yep -And a button's gonna cause a post, right?
-Yep -一个按钮会引起一个帖子，对吧？
So this will go and be handled by the delete handler.
这将由删除处理程序处理
But we also need that route information, we need that id because we're gonna delete a particular customer.
但是我们也需要那个路线信息，我们需要那个ID，因为我们要删除一个特定的客户
-So you need the content ID, yep -Customer ID, exactly
-所以你需要内容ID，是吧 -确切地说是客户ID
All right, and then none of this is hooked up.
好吧，然后这些都没有连接起来
So you mentioned something, voice of the people at home,about the button being a post.
所以你提到了一些东西，家里人的声音，关于按钮的帖子
Yes, it is going to post back and then we're gonna need to handle that behavior differently than the Create page.
是的，它将发布回，然后我们需要处理不同于创建页面的行为
So then I'll just put a link at the bottom there for Create.
然后我会在底部放置一个链接来创建
So I'm just gonna hit Refresh.
所以我只需要刷新一下
-So let's see if the Create -Here's our Create.
-我们看看是不是创造 -这是我们的创造
That still works.
这仍然有效
-Okay -I hover over that.
-Okay -我犹豫了一下
Nothing's happening because we don't have an edit.
没有任何事情发生，因为我们没有编辑
We never made an edit page, and I hit Delete You should.
我们从来没有编辑页面，我点击删除你应该
It's gonna crash cuz it's like I don't know what you're doing, right?
它会崩溃，因为我不知道你在做什么，对吧？
It's just in the middle of something and it's confused cuz that's not what I asked it to do.
它只是在某个事物的中间，它很混乱，因为这不是我要它做的
Okay, so we've got some fixing up to do.
好的，所以我们有一些修复工作要做
Let's try Delete first -Okay. All right, so let's go over here.
让我们先试着删除，好吧。好的，让我们过去
We made an OnGet -Let's go and make an OnDelete.
我们制作了一个 OnGET ，让我们去做一个 OnDelphi
-Okay -Same thing as before with an IActionResult, except now we're gonna say on and this is kinda weird, OnPostDelete.
-Okay -和以前一样，除了现在我们要说，这有点奇怪，OnPostDelete
The verb delete is a real HTTP verb,but it's not really often used from a browser's perspective.
动词删除是一个真正的HTTP动词，但它实际上并不经常从浏览器的角度使用
It's usually done as it's piggybacked on post.
它通常是背负在 post
We use post to pass in basically all kinds of information.
我们利用 post 基本上传递各种信息
Whenever we hit Submit on a form, we're posting that form.
每当我们在一个表单上点击提交时，我们就发布了这个表单
We're adding in, I think we said, page-handler delete.
我们添加，我想我们说，页面处理删除
So that is gonna be here, OnPostDelete.
那就在这里，OnPostDelete
And now we're going to say,a customer, customer singular.
现在我们要说，客户，客户单一
And we'll go and get that customer out of the database.
我们去把客户从数据库中拿出来
Before we delete it we gotta go and get it to make sure it's there,I say find, by that ID that got passed in.
在删除之前，我们必须去拿它，确保它在那里，我说，找到，通过那个ID
So now we gotta check to see if that customer's null or not, cuz if it's null, then we don't even bother.
所以现在我们必须检查这个客户是否为空，因为如果它是空的，那么我们甚至不用麻烦
If it's not null, do something.
如果它不是空的，就做点什么
And then we can go and Redirect.
然后我们可以重定向
To a page.
一页
To a page, exactly, thank you.
一页，确切地说，谢谢
So here, we're gonna remove it from the database.
所以，我们将从数据库中删除它
And we are doing it in a memory database but it doesn't matter because if it was a regular database it would remove it for us, as well, that's what's nice about any framework.
我们在内存数据库中做这件事，但这并不重要，因为如果它是一个常规数据库，它也会为我们移除它，这就是任何框架的好处
I'm not a very good typer.
我不是一个很好的人
So we remove the customer and then we go and we save those changes.
因此，我们删除客户，然后我们去，我们保存这些变化
-Okay -And then I would expect it would then redirect to the page,the same page.
-Okay -然后我预计它会重定向到页面，同一个页面
Yes. And I would expect that it would disappear from that list because it's going to go back to the database and build the list again.
对。我希望它会从那个列表中消失，因为它将回到数据库并重新构建列表
-Does that make sense? -It does, it sure does.
-这有道理吗？ -是的，的确如此
I think that's what it will do.
我想这就是它所要做的
So we cross our fingers and hope that it works.
所以我们交叉手指，希望它能起作用
And if it doesn't, we learn.
如果没有，我们就学会了
-Okay -That's not a good name.
-Okay -那不是个好名字
All right, we're deleting you.
好吧，我们正在删除你
Okay, I'm fine with that.
好吧，我很好
-It does work the way you want -Yeah, it does work
-它可以按你想要的方式工作 -是的，它确实有效
-Fire, fire, fire -Deal, deal, deal.
-火，火，火 -交易，交易，交易
-Fancy pants -But now if we edit it.
-花式裤子 -但现在如果我们编辑它
Doesn't work because Edit doesn't exist.
不起作用，因为编辑不存在
And it is not there.
它不在那里
All right, so let's go and do edit, then.
好吧，那么我们去编辑一下吧
So we'll do what you said before, add razor page.
所以我们会做你之前说过的，添加 RaZor Page
Call it Edit, now I know you like routing.
称之为编辑，现在我知道你喜欢路由
Routing is one of your favorite things about ASP.NET.
路由是 ASP.NET 最喜欢的事情之一
So this Edit page is gonna be the first time that we've ever had a page that took in information.
所以这个编辑页面将是我们第一次有一个信息页面
-Okay -Where does that go to pass in the ID?
-Okay -好吧，ID会在哪里通过？
-So up there at page? -Right, quote quotes.
-在页面上吗？ -右，引号
Yeah, and curly brackets.
是的，还有卷曲的括号
-Yeah -ID.
-是的 -ID
I mean int.
我的意思是 INT
Okay so the ID is of type int.
好的，ID 是 int 型的
Yes. That's the type hint.
对。这就是类型提示
So this is saying edit slash 3.
这就是编辑斜线 3
So you'd see it in the browser,that's what it would look like.
所以你会在浏览器中看到它，这就是它的样子
Okay.
可以
We have our Edit model, and then here, at the top, we might have Edit, we could actually add a little bit of text here.
我们有我们的编辑模型，然后在这里，在顶部，我们可能有编辑，我们实际上可以在这里添加一点文本
We could say Edit Customer.
我们可以说编辑客户
And then we could say -Dash Model?
-然后我们可以说 -破折号模型？
@Model.Customer, but again, we're not getting IntelliSense,why not?
@Model.Customer, 但是，我们没有得到智能感知，为什么不呢？
Because the page model is different for each page.
因为页面模型对于每个页面都是不同的
-Exactly -So let's go look at the one for Edit
-确切 -让我们看看编辑的那个
So I'm gonna.
所以我要去
-You're gonna take, yeah -Borrow again
-你会接受的，是的 -再借钱
Certainly I could make another class, a base class, that would pull that AppDBContext in so I wouldn't have to keep copy-pasting that because at some point the copy-pasting becomes tedious.
当然，我可以做另一个类，一个基类，它将拉那个AppDcRead，所以我不必保持复制粘贴，因为在某些时候，复制粘贴变得乏味
And you want to keep it dry, right.
你想保持干燥，对吧？
Don't repeat yourself.
不要重复你自己
You probably want that to survive the journey right?
你可能想让它在旅途中幸存？
Yeah.
是啊
Okay.
So we want to survive the journey,with bindproperty, okay.
所以我们想在旅途中幸存下来
So I go back over to our page, and let's see if that worked.
所以我回到我们的页面，让我们看看这是否有效
And it did, that's nice.
的确如此，那很好
Yes, it did.
是的，的确如此
So now we can say, we are Model.Customer.Id, so we can say, Edit Customer for, or whatever.
所以现在我们可以说，我们是Mault.Customer .ID，所以我们可以说，编辑客户，或者什么
And then form, and then a form post, and there's some lots of cool ways to make your forms easier to write.
然后形成一个表单，还有一些很酷的方法让你的表单更容易写
If you find writing forms tedious, there's a really great way to write forms that is called Emmet.
如果你觉得书写形式冗长乏味，那么有一种很好的方式来编写被称为Emmet的表单
-What is Emmet? -You've never heard of Emmet?
-Emmet是什么？ -你从没听说过Emmet吗？
E-m-m-e-t, it's like the name, the person's name Emmet.
E-m-m-e-t, 就像名字，人的名字Emmet
Okay. And it's a way of describing what you want like a feel like trt.
Okay. 这是一种描述你想要的感觉的方式
TR TD times three and then you'd hit tab and then it would go and expand it, it's a way to write tags for HTML really really fast.
TR TD 时间三，然后你会点击标签，然后它会去扩展它，这是一个写HTML的标签真的非常快的方法
-Is it built in? -It's built into Visual Studio code but it is not built in to Visual Studio yet.
-它是内置的吗？ -它内置到VisualStudio代码中，但尚未在VisualStudio中内置
-Okay -Notice how I got this here, soon as I said ASP net four.
-Okay -注意我是如何得到这个的，很快我就说了ASP NET four
Yeah, it gave you Input four, rather.
是的，它给了你输入四，而不是
It got that, this is really nice, right?
这真是太好了，对吧？
So I can go and fill out these forms really quickly and I don't have to worry about that's gonna happen on the server side.
所以我可以很快地填写这些表格，我不必担心会在服务器端发生
Okay, so then we'll say a label, and this is a label also for.
好的，那我们就说一个标签，这也是一个标签
The customer.
顾客
Customer's name which is nice and then we'll say, give you another div, And then within there we'll have an input.
客户的名字是好的，然后我们会说，给你另一个div，然后在里面我们会有一个输入
For Customer.Name.
为了 Customer.Name
And then you can do the validation again, right?
然后你再做验证，对吧？
Yeah I'll do some, but I can do validation two different ways.
是的，我会做一些，但是我可以用两种不同的方式来验证
I could do the validation summary or we can do it like this, which is nice.
我可以做验证总结，或者我们可以这样做，这是很好的
And what are the key differences?
关键的区别是什么？
This one is, you have total control of what it looks like.
这是，你完全控制它的样子
You can put it anywhere up or down.
你可以把它放在任何地方
Okay. And this is just a bulleted list that's a roll up.
可以。这只是一个清单，是一个卷起来
Okay. Of all of the stuff.
可以。所有的东西
Totally up to you how you wanna do things.
完全取决于你如何做事情
This is all inside of a form, right?
这都是一种形式，对吧？
So you want to save it, right?
所以你想保存它，对吧？
Yeah, we're going to need a save button.
是的，我们需要一个保存按钮
So we'll put our button at the bottom,and it's just a regular old submit, nothing fancy about it.
所以我们把按钮放在底部，它只是一个普通的老提交，没有什么新奇之处
We're going to want to load this up and save it.
它会说保存
And it'll say save.
我们要把它装入并保存它
And have validation.
并进行验证
We've done all that very nicely like this, and we just wanna confirm like you said on the backend that we do the right thing.
我们已经做得非常好，我们只想确认你在后端说过我们做正确的事情
So on the get, actually let's do this.
所以在 GET 上，实际上让我们这样做
Let's run it first and then we'll try it again because right now we haven't hooked anything up.
让我们先运行它，然后我们再试试，因为现在我们还没有钓到任何东西
We haven't got it from the database we haven't updated from the database.
我们没有从数据库中得到它，我们还没有从数据库中更新
But I would expect the links to at least work.
但我希望这些链接至少能起作用
Cuz now there is an Edit page.
是啊。因为现在有一个编辑页面
If there's not, then maybe I forgot something.
如果没有，那么也许我忘了什么
Okay, look in the corner there.
好的，看看那边的角落
-Okay -It's kind of hard for me to do that.
-Okay -这对我来说有点难
I can take a screenshot but I can't really take a screenshot.
我可以截屏，但我真的不能截图
-Let's do this -We'll take a snipping tool.
-让我们这样做 -我们将采取剪断工具
Give it a delay of two seconds.
耽搁两秒钟
You're that fast? I am.
你那么快？我是
So Edit/1 right,so the route got built by the fact that it was in the Edit.
所以编辑/ 1是正确的，所以路线是建立在编辑的事实上的
And then you had added that ID at the top there.
然后你在上面添加了ID
So this is nice because we didn't have to hard code what a link looked like.
所以这很好，因为我们不必硬编码一个链接看起来像什么
That's really important.
这很重要
We said, make me a link that takes me here.
我们说，让我成为一个带我来到这里的纽带
We didn't say make me a link that looks like this.
我们并没有说让我成为这样的一个链接
And if we changed our things later, then it would change for us, which is nice.
如果我们以后改变我们的事情，那么它会为我们改变，这很好
So here,if I click on that, I assume it'll just do, yeah, nothing.
在这里，如果我点击它，我想它会做的，是的，没什么
So it's like, , I don't have anything there.
就这样， blegh ，我什么都没有
It doesn't know about customer yet because we have the bind,but we never loaded the customers.
它不知道客户，因为我们有绑定，但我们从来没有加载客户
So let's go and do our stuff again, we're gonna have our action result and here we're gonna say OnGet, of course,int id, that's gonna get passed in automatically because of the way we set up our routes, that's nice.
所以，让我们再去做我们的事情，我们将有我们的行动结果，在这里，我们要说OnGET，当然，INT ID，这将是通过自动的，因为我们设置我们的路线的方式，这是很好的
By default, will just return to page, but here we'll say Customer, the one above Go and get it from the database.
默认情况下，将只返回页面，但在这里，我们将说，客户，上面的一个，并从数据库中获取
-And find it, okay -Yeah, so FindAsync, kind of a standard thing, you could pass in more complicated queries, and get it other ways.
-找到它 ,okay -Yeah, 所以 FindAsync, 这是一个标准的东西，你可以传递更复杂的查询，并用其他方法得到
If it's null, freak out.
如果它是空的，反常
-Right? -Yeah. If (Customers == null),I don't know, let's put them back to index.
-Right? -Yeah. 如果 (Customers == null),我不知道，让我们把它们放回 index
It's Customer, right?
那是 Customer, 对吧?
Yes, pardon me, Customer.
Yes, 对不起, Customer.
Okay, RedirectToPage("/Index"); a lot of typing,but we don't wanna hide anything from you.
Okay, RedirectToPage("/Index"); 很多打字，但我们不想漏下任何东西
Keeping it 100.
保持100
We are absolutely keeping it 100,so this should that up and give us a form, with the customer in it.
我们绝对保持100，所以这应该是，并给我们一个形式，与客户在其中
Let's see if it does, cuz we added that bind property,which you said, what did you call it?
让我们看看它是否，因为我们添加了绑定属性，你说，你把它叫做什么？
Surviving the journey.
在旅途中幸存下来
You saw that interest movie really survive the journey.
你看那部有趣的电影真的能在旅途中幸存下来
Don't tell me what happens at the end?
不要告诉我最后会发生什么？
-So I've been -I don't wanna know
-所以我去过 -我不想知道
Okay, and then I hit Edit, and then it works.
Okay, 然后我点击编辑，然后它就工作了
-Exactly -Right.
-确切地 -正确的
-So what happens if you change it around? -If I change it
-如果你改变它会发生什么？ -如果我改变它
probably nothing Right,cuz we don't have our post.
可能没有什么是正确的，因为我们没有我们的岗位
Exactly.
准确的
Exactly, so we've got our get.
没错，我们拿到了
But we don't have our post.
但是我们没有我们的岗位
You could kind of copy that.
你可以 copy 一下
Yes, I think there's a way to actually link that whole thing quickly, but we'll say, OnPostAsync All right,the very end we will do that Redirect.
是的，我认为有一种方法可以很快地把整件事情联系起来，但是我们会说， OnPASTASYNC 好了，最后我们会做重定向
-To the index page? -To the index page, exactly
-Okay -What do we do?
Well, we've got that model state valid issue.
Yeah, so if not model.
Not ModelState.IsValid.
Yeah, we want it to return to the page.
-Okay -Aah, Page
See, if you try to type too fast to impress people, and it just ends up making you look silly.
Okay, now this one is an interesting one.
Cuz you want to attach it to the database.
Yeah, so what we're doing is,we're modifying something that's all ready in the database.
So what we're trying to do is take this customer that we are recurrently editing.
So it's in a cart state.
Attach that customer in the state of it in the database,we're going to mark that as Modified.
And this bit here.
It shouldn't be there, yeah -Add the using statement, there we go.
And now it's turned blue, okay.
Now, we don't know if it's going to work, because someone else could be simultaneously editing at the same time.
Exactly, so you want to do a try and catch.
Can do a try, maybe it'll work, maybe it won't.
And the exception that we're gonna catch for,is called aDbUpdateConcurrencyException.
So just in case someone's doing-
-If someone's in there at the same time -Exactly what it says.
-Exactly what it is -Okay, so you're going to wait for changes?
Go on 'await' and say SaveChangesAsync, and presumably that'll work fine.
If it doesn't- We'll have to throw an exception?
Now there's different arguments about the right way to do this, but for now I'm gonna go and say, Customer, and this is kind of cool.
Customer.Id, see how I'm getting IntelliSense inside the string?
We can do whatever we want to about that concurrency exception, maybe even pass it in as an inner exception.
But the fact is, actually, that would be a good idea,we'll pass that in, along for the ride.
We wanna give a message to somebody that bad stuff has happened.
All right,that should be, I think we always gonna create only.
-And we do -We've done the create.
-Let's go see -I think the create was a post.
-Yeah -The read is the for loop.
The delete was also a post, but with a delete sidecar,along for the ride.
-So, Create, Dan -Break points from before.
-Yeah. I will remove those -I think you still have, okay.
Continue, we'll bump into them if we have more.
-Fancy pants -Beyonce.
-That's a good point -Edit
-Carter -Carter Knowles.
-Yeah -Don't get it twisted.
-Delete everyone else who is not worthy -So
-See, it works -It does work.
There you go, taking care of business, cool.
-So, let's think about that -So, that's pretty sweet.
-It is -If we go back, and just kind of review particularly,this bit here we've got our edit.
With the route id where we did not see
-Where are we reaching -out right now?
I'm sorry this is index.
-Okay -Right?
So here we got an edit.
I wanna point out how it looks in the code, and then compare that to how it looks ultimately in the code, right?
When it makes it all the way back to the browser.
-See? -It's in.
So that came from, this seems like a little more.
You might be asking yourself,why you don't just hard code that?
But routes change, pages change, things get moved around..
Now, this one is a little bit more interesting here,because you might have multiple buttons on the page that do different stuff.
So then, you can give them a handler name
Right? I could have delete.
I could have bold face Beyonce, I could have all caps
We could have whatever.
You're not limited to one button.
A submit button can have, you could have multiple submits,still passing numbers, like in this case id.
-Yeah -And this is an ampersand.
-Yeah -Multiple handlers, delete, promote whatever.
-Save -Save exactly
-Okay -And what's cool about that, is that then that word delete If we look at the behind is this word.
So I think you could even go like on post "foo" async, or whatever, as long as it lines up because you're saying on post and then some handler.
-Yes -That cool?
That is cool. And the handler is literally you could say Let me stop our debugging here.
You gonna try the foo?
Right I can do whatever, it doesn't matter.
That word is totally up to you.
So I don't need to test that.
-You just trust me -You don't trust me?
-Yeah, sure -All right let's test it then.
-Let's test it -That gives you a lot of flexibility with buttons, so I say foo right there.
-I go over here -We say foo.
And there you go.
So while that's loading? What were you gonna say?
No, no, no, I trust you ish.
-Trust you ish? -Yeah.
That's pretty good, I'll take that.
Let's go and add people.
-Okay -That was foo.
How did f oo know it was delete?
Because it doesn't matter that it was named Foo.
It's just a handler name.
And if we confirm it Did I pass it?
-Nope -This is create, sorry.
There you go there's a delete.
Okay see it says handler equals foo.
-Yes, okay, yes -And then, I just happened to name this handler foo also.
-Yes, yeah -So the point is, it lined up.
And that's how you can have unlimited verbs.
And then at that point, it just did the thing and removed it from the database.
-Cool? -Cool. So,we saw lots of different handlers, like gets and posts, and custom handlers like delete.
-Yeah -We saw some tag helpers, that will generate buttons and links for us.
-We saw layout pages -We saw validation.
We saw validation both summary and individual.
-And yeah -Yeah lots of little bit about routing and a little bit more detail.
We saw routing,and then specifically, actually one important thing we can point out about routing as well.
If I click edit Did we, I shut the app down again.
You had said ID:int
-Yes -Where int was a number, correct?
It would be interesting.
So just confirm that, if we put in Submit Query, edit, she is one.
Put in an ID that is not an int.
You should get a You simply get a 404,you don't get a 500.
It's not an error.
It's a route that doesn't exist.
We don't have an edit that takes a string.
So that's another really,really important thing to point out about routing, and why that little bit up there was so significant?
And then soon, in the intermediate sections, we will learn a little bit more about web APIs, and url, and mixing and matching pages as well Yeah.
Can we take a break and come back with a little bit of logging?
Yes we will